const arr = [{"id":0,"info":"4th-year/orthopedics/2022","question":"A 55-year-old male presented to the clinic with the complaint of fever, weight loss, and back pain. On physical examination, extreme tenderness was noticed at the lumbar vertebrae. Magnetic resonance imaging (MRI) of the lumbar spine showed evidence of Pott’s disease. Which of the following organisms is most commonly involved in this disease process?","answers":[{"option":"Pseudomonas aeruginosa","bool":false},{"option":"β-hemolytic streptococci","bool":false},{"option":"Mycobacterium tuberculosis","bool":true},{"option":"Staphylococcus aureus","bool":false},{"option":"Salmonella species","bool":false}]},{"id":1,"info":"4th-year/orthopedics/2022","question":"A 58-year-old woman discussed osteoporosis with her physician. She was worried that for a couple of years, after menopause, she was at an increased risk for osteoporosis. Which of the following is prescribed initially to prevent the risk of future problems?","answers":[{"option":"Infusion of potent bisphosphonates at large intervals","bool":false},{"option":"Selective estrogen receptor modulators (SERMs)","bool":false},{"option":"Anabolic agents","bool":false},{"option":"Hormone replacement therapy","bool":false},{"option":"Maintaining adequate calcium and vitamin D through diet modification and/or supplementation","bool":true}]},{"id":2,"info":"4th-year/orthopedics/2022","question":"Which of the following can be caused by inhalation of coal dust?","answers":[{"option":"Anthracosis","bool":true},{"option":"Siderosis","bool":false},{"option":"Silicosis","bool":false},{"option":"Farmer’s lung","bool":false},{"option":"Bagassosis","bool":false}]},{"id":3,"info":"4th-year/orthopedics/2022","question":"What will be the primary cause of death from massive acetaminophen overdose?","answers":[{"option":"Acute nephropathy","bool":false},{"option":"AV conduction disturbance","bool":false},{"option":"Liver failure","bool":true},{"option":"Status asthmaticus","bool":false},{"option":"Status epilepticus","bool":false}]},{"id":4,"info":"4th-year/orthopedics/2022","question":"Which of the following is a common early complication of a supracondylar fracture of the humerus?","answers":[{"option":"Brachial artery damage","bool":true},{"option":"Elbow stiffness","bool":false},{"option":"Ulnar nerve injury","bool":false},{"option":"Volkmann's contracture","bool":false},{"option":"Radial artery damage","bool":false}]},{"id":5,"info":"4th-year/orthopedics/2022","question":"Which of the following autoimmune diseases is associated with the highest rate of malignancy?","answers":[{"option":"Sjogren's syndrome","bool":false},{"option":"Systemic lupus erythematosus","bool":false},{"option":"Systemic sclerosis","bool":false},{"option":"Rheumatoid arthritis","bool":false},{"option":"Dermatomyositis","bool":true}]},{"id":6,"info":"4th-year/orthopedics/2022","question":"Which of the following is the best first step of management for osteoarthritis?","answers":[{"option":"Anti-TNF therapy","bool":false},{"option":"Heavy weightlifting","bool":false},{"option":"Joint replacement","bool":false},{"option":"Weight loss and mild exercise","bool":true},{"option":"Bisphosphonates","bool":false}]},{"id":7,"info":"4th-year/orthopedics/2022","question":"What are the effects of radiation in the eye?","answers":[{"option":"Keratitis","bool":false},{"option":"Glaucoma","bool":false},{"option":"Conjuctivitis","bool":false},{"option":"Cataract","bool":true},{"option":"Anterior uveitis","bool":false}]},{"id":8,"info":"4th-year/orthopedics/2022","question":"Which of the following drugs is effective in managing acute gouty arthritis, ankylosing spondylitis, and also accelerates closure of patent ductus arteriosus in premature infants?","answers":[{"option":"Gold","bool":false},{"option":"Methotrexate","bool":false},{"option":"Phenylbutazone","bool":false},{"option":"Ketorolac","bool":false},{"option":"Indomethachin","bool":true}]},{"id":9,"info":"4th-year/orthopedics/2022","question":"A 28-year-old male presents to the clinic because of swollen, painful small joints in his right hand. On examination, there is a scaly rash on the extensor surfaces of the skin and scalp. Which of the following diagnosis is most consistent with this case?","answers":[{"option":"Systemic lupus erythematosus","bool":false},{"option":"Psoriatric arthritis","bool":true},{"option":"Rheumatoid arthritis","bool":false},{"option":"Overlap syndrome","bool":false},{"option":"Enteropathic arthritis","bool":false}]},{"id":10,"info":"4th-year/orthopedics/2022","question":"Osteomyelitis is most commonly a bacterial infection that arises via hematogenous spread. Which of the following organisms is the most common cause of this disease?","answers":[{"option":"Streptococcus pyogenes","bool":false},{"option":"Pseudomonas","bool":false},{"option":"Staphylococcus aureus","bool":true},{"option":"Streptococcus pneumoniae","bool":false},{"option":"Bacillus anthracis","bool":false}]},{"id":11,"info":"4th-year/orthopedics/2022","question":"Which of the following is the most common complication of talus neck fracture?","answers":[{"option":"Varus malunion","bool":false},{"option":"Tibiotalar arthritis","bool":false},{"option":"Avascular necrosis","bool":true},{"option":"Subtalar arthritis","bool":false},{"option":"Nonunion","bool":false}]},{"id":12,"info":"4th-year/orthopedics/2022","question":"A patient with a history of chronic hypertension develops an acute gout attack. He is currently on a four-drug regimen, consisting of hydrochlorothiazide, valsartan, amlodipine, and atenolol. What is the most likely reason for the precipitation of his gout attack?","answers":[{"option":"None of these","bool":false},{"option":"Valsartan","bool":false},{"option":"Atenolol","bool":false},{"option":"Hydrochlorothiazide","bool":true},{"option":"Amlodipine","bool":false}]},{"id":13,"info":"4th-year/orthopedics/2022","question":"A 40-year-old female patient presents with back pain and extreme weight loss. She was diagnosed with breast cancer 5 years ago but she denied chemotherapy or any other form of treatment. What will be the next best investigation?","answers":[{"option":"Bone scan","bool":true},{"option":"Ultrasound","bool":false},{"option":"Spinal MRI","bool":false},{"option":"Chest X-ray","bool":false},{"option":"Mammogram","bool":false}]},{"id":14,"info":"4th-year/orthopedics/2022","question":"An 8-year-old male child presents with unilateral thigh swelling and a restricted range of motion. What is the most likely diagnosis?","answers":[{"option":"Congenital dysplasia of hip","bool":false},{"option":"Talipes equinovarus","bool":false},{"option":"Achondroplasia","bool":false},{"option":"Leg perthes disease","bool":true},{"option":"Slipped capital femoral epiphysis","bool":false}]},{"id":15,"info":"4th-year/orthopedics/2022","question":"Which of the following drugs is not contraindicated in a patient with hemophilia?","answers":[{"option":"Acetaminophen","bool":true},{"option":"Ibuprofen","bool":false},{"option":"Diclofenac","bool":false},{"option":"Naproxen","bool":false},{"option":"Aspirin","bool":false}]},{"id":16,"info":"4th-year/orthopedics/2022","question":"A 16-year-old child comes with his parents to the outpatient department. The parents complain to the doctor that their child has a short stature and has not developed puberty yet. The doctor examines the child and concludes that the bone age is less than the chronological age and diagnoses the child with constitutional growth delay. The parents are worried about the final height of the child. What would be the best treatment for this child?","answers":[{"option":"Low dose androgen therapy","bool":false},{"option":"Surgery to increase the height of femur","bool":false},{"option":"Reassurance and counselling","bool":true},{"option":"No treatment and the final height is decreased.","bool":false},{"option":"Growth hormone injections","bool":false}]},{"id":17,"info":"4th-year/orthopedics/2022","question":"A young gymnast comes to the outpatient department (OPD) with the complaint of lower back pain. The clinician after taking radiographs concluded that there is a defect in the pars interarticularis. What is this condition called?","answers":[{"option":"Spondylolisthesis","bool":false},{"option":"Spondylolysis","bool":true},{"option":"Spine osteoarthritis","bool":false},{"option":"Psoriatic arthritis","bool":false},{"option":"Bamboo spine","bool":false}]},{"id":18,"info":"4th-year/orthopedics/2022","question":"A man with a history of a fall presents to the outpatient department with the complaint of pain in the lower back. On examination, the power in the lower limbs is 2/5 and the perianal sensation is intact. There is no urinary retention. What is the most probable diagnosis?","answers":[{"option":"Fracture of vertebra only","bool":false},{"option":"Cauda equina syndrome","bool":false},{"option":"Complete cord injury","bool":false},{"option":"Incomplete cord injury","bool":true},{"option":"No cord injury","bool":false}]},{"id":19,"info":"4th-year/orthopedics/2022","question":"A young male with a history of heavy weight lifting presents to the emergency with the complaint of severe radiating pain in both limbs and perineal numbness. On examination, there is motor weakness in both lower limbs. What is the most probable diagnosis?","answers":[{"option":"Brown sequard syndrome","bool":false},{"option":"Fracture of vertebral body","bool":false},{"option":"Lumbar disc herniation","bool":false},{"option":"Cauda equina syndrome","bool":true},{"option":"Complete cord transaction","bool":false}]},{"id":20,"info":"4th-year/orthopedics/2022","question":"A 30-year-old male comes to the outpatient department with a complaint of acute onset shoulder pain. On examination, the external rotation is possible and there is a sub-acromial calcification seen on a plain radiograph. What is the most probable diagnosis?","answers":[{"option":"Calcific tendinitis","bool":true},{"option":"Adhesive capsulitis","bool":false},{"option":"Rheumatoid arthritis","bool":false},{"option":"Frozen shoulder","bool":false},{"option":"Rotator cuff tear","bool":false}]},{"id":21,"info":"4th-year/orthopedics/2022","question":"A patient presents to the outpatient department with the complaint of bone pain and deafness for the past few days. He also complains about increasing hat size. What is the most probable diagnosis?","answers":[{"option":"Osteoporosis","bool":false},{"option":"Osteitis fibrosa cystica","bool":false},{"option":"Paget disease of bone","bool":true},{"option":"Primary hyperparathyroidism","bool":false},{"option":"Osteopetrosis","bool":false}]},{"id":22,"info":"4th-year/orthopedics/2022","question":"Which of the following effects of morphine is the most resistant to development of tolerance?","answers":[{"option":"Euphoria","bool":false},{"option":"Cough suppression","bool":false},{"option":"Respiratory depression","bool":false},{"option":"Constipation","bool":true},{"option":"Emesis","bool":false}]},{"id":23,"info":"4th-year/orthopedics/2022","question":"Which of the following cases produces \"light bulb\" sign on X-ray anteroposterior view?","answers":[{"option":"Posterior shoulder dislocation","bool":true},{"option":"Acromioclavicular fracture","bool":false},{"option":"Anterior shoulder dislocation","bool":false},{"option":"Proximal humerus fracture","bool":false},{"option":"Clavicular shaft fracture","bool":false}]},{"id":24,"info":"4th-year/orthopedics/2022","question":"What is the most common management of clavicular fractures?","answers":[{"option":"Plating","bool":false},{"option":"Conservative","bool":true},{"option":"Screwing","bool":false},{"option":"Nailing","bool":false},{"option":"Wiring","bool":false}]},{"id":25,"info":"4th-year/orthopedics/2022","question":"Which of the following is the most appropriate sequence of events involved in the healing of fractures?","answers":[{"option":"Hematoma-inflammation-soft callus-hard callus-remodeling","bool":true},{"option":"Soft callus-hard callus-inflammation-hematoma-remodeling","bool":false},{"option":"Inflammation-remodeling-hematoma-soft callus-hard callus","bool":false},{"option":"Hematoma-soft callus-hard callus-inflammation-remodeling","bool":false},{"option":"Inflammation-hematoma-soft callus-hard callus-remodeling","bool":false}]},{"id":26,"info":"4th-year/orthopedics/2022","question":"What is the mechanism by which ethanol increases acetaminophen toxicity?","answers":[{"option":"Activates P450 to convert acetaminophen to toxic metabolites","bool":true},{"option":"Inactivates P450 to inhibit acetaminophen metabolism","bool":false},{"option":"Non-competitively inhibits the enzymes responsible for acetaminophen metabolism","bool":false},{"option":"Reduces renal clearance of acetaminophen and its metabolites","bool":false},{"option":"Competitively inhibits the enzymes responsible for acetaminophen metabolism","bool":false}]},{"id":27,"info":"4th-year/orthopedics/2022","question":"During which weeks of gestation is a fetus most prone to developing teratogenic limb defects?","answers":[{"option":"12-13 weeks","bool":false},{"option":"1-2 weeks","bool":false},{"option":"7-8 weeks","bool":false},{"option":"10-11 weeks","bool":false},{"option":"4-5 weeks","bool":true}]},{"id":28,"info":"4th-year/orthopedics/2022","question":"What is the most accurate definition of spondylolisthesis?","answers":[{"option":"Degeneration of a vertebral body and the disc under it","bool":false},{"option":"Slipping of a vertebra over the one below it","bool":true},{"option":"Degeneration of a vertebral body","bool":false},{"option":"Fracture through the pars interarticularis of a vertebra","bool":false},{"option":"Inflammation of the joints between the vertebrae","bool":false}]},{"id":29,"info":"4th-year/orthopedics/2022","question":"According to the Salter-Harris classification, which fracture type looks normal on an X-ray?","answers":[{"option":"Type 5","bool":true},{"option":"Type 1","bool":false},{"option":"Type 2","bool":false},{"option":"Type 4","bool":false},{"option":"Type 3","bool":false}]},{"id":30,"info":"4th-year/orthopedics/2022","question":"A worker in a marble-cutting and sand-blasting industry may have which of the following occupational diseases?","answers":[{"option":"Berylliosis","bool":false},{"option":"Silicosis","bool":true},{"option":"Anthracosis","bool":false},{"option":"Bagassosis","bool":false},{"option":"Byssinosis","bool":false}]},{"id":31,"info":"4th-year/orthopedics/2022","question":"Which of the following is absorbed by the ozone at the stratosphere?","answers":[{"option":"Dust particles","bool":false},{"option":"Gases","bool":false},{"option":"Pollutants","bool":false},{"option":"Smell","bool":false},{"option":"Radiation","bool":true}]},{"id":32,"info":"4th-year/orthopedics/2022","question":"What is the mode of spread of snake venom within the human body?","answers":[{"option":"Venous","bool":false},{"option":"Cardiac circulation","bool":false},{"option":"Respiratory","bool":false},{"option":"Lymphatic","bool":true},{"option":"Arterial","bool":false}]},{"id":33,"info":"4th-year/orthopedics/2022","question":"According to the Cierny-Mader classification, which of the following statements is not true?","answers":[{"option":"Stage 1 is medullary osteomyelitis","bool":false},{"option":"Stage 2 is superficial osteomyelitis which is localized to the bone surface","bool":false},{"option":"Stage 2 is localized osteomyelitis with portion of medullary involvement and dead cortical bone","bool":true},{"option":"Host factor A denotes no co-morbidities, B denotes immunocompromised host and C denotes severe disease","bool":false},{"option":"Stage 4 is diffuse osteomyelitis","bool":false}]},{"id":34,"info":"4th-year/orthopedics/2022","question":"A middle-aged woman presents to the clinic with a complaint of swelling on the left side of the neck. Investigation reveals an increase in serum calcium levels. What is the most common cause of primary hyperparathyroidism?","answers":[{"option":"Parathyroid carcinoma","bool":false},{"option":"Primary diffuse hyperplasia","bool":false},{"option":"Primary nodular hyperplasia","bool":false},{"option":"Familial hypocalciuric hypercalcemia","bool":false},{"option":"Parathyroid adenoma","bool":true}]},{"id":35,"info":"4th-year/orthopedics/2022","question":"An elderly man presents to the clinic with a large painful mass in his shoulder. Biopsy shows anaplastic chondrocytes and hyaline cartilage matrix. Which of the following statements is true regarding this lesion?","answers":[{"option":"It is inflammatory in nature","bool":false},{"option":"Some of its variants are clear cell and mesenchymal","bool":true},{"option":"Most low grade lesions show anaplasia and abnormal mitoses","bool":false},{"option":"Distal extremities are commonly involved","bool":false},{"option":"High grade lesions favor lymphatic spread","bool":false}]},{"id":36,"info":"4th-year/orthopedics/2022","question":"A patient presents with a 12 cm laceration on the right shin with the protrusion of his fractured tibia through the laceration. According to the Gustilo-Anderson classification,  what is the type of this fracture?","answers":[{"option":"Type 3a","bool":false},{"option":"Type 1","bool":false},{"option":"Type 3b","bool":true},{"option":"Type 2","bool":false},{"option":"Type 3c","bool":false}]},{"id":37,"info":"4th-year/orthopedics/2022","question":"Which of the following structures is the base of the odontoid process?","answers":[{"option":"C3","bool":false},{"option":"Atlas","bool":false},{"option":"C4","bool":false},{"option":"C5","bool":false},{"option":"Axis","bool":true}]},{"id":38,"info":"4th-year/orthopedics/2022","question":"Which of the following vertebrae is involved in Jefferson's fracture?","answers":[{"option":"C3","bool":false},{"option":"C1","bool":true},{"option":"C5","bool":false},{"option":"C4","bool":false},{"option":"C2","bool":false}]},{"id":39,"info":"4th-year/orthopedics/2022","question":"A 7-year-old boy was prescribed an anti-pyretic for influenza. After 4 days of treatment, he died on the 5th day. An autopsy revealed microvesicular fatty infiltration in the liver, heart, and kidneys, and cerebral edema was also present. Which anti-pyretic was the boy using?","answers":[{"option":"Acetaminophen","bool":false},{"option":"Aspirin","bool":true},{"option":"Ketorolac","bool":false},{"option":"Piroxicam","bool":false},{"option":"Ibuprofen","bool":false}]},{"id":40,"info":"4th-year/orthopedics/2022","question":"Which of these is a side effect of meperidine only at high or repeated doses?","answers":[{"option":"Constipation","bool":false},{"option":"Miosis","bool":false},{"option":"Biliary tract spasm","bool":false},{"option":"Psychosis and seizure","bool":true},{"option":"Heightened response to pain","bool":false}]},{"id":41,"info":"4th-year/orthopedics/2022","question":"A newborn is brought dead to the outpatient department. He presents with a foot deformity where inward deformity of the heel, varus deformity of the forefoot, and plantar flexion are noted. What is the most likely diagnosis for this patient?","answers":[{"option":"Developmental dysplasia of the hip with polydactyly","bool":false},{"option":"Talipes equinovalgus with neural tube defects","bool":false},{"option":"Talipes equinovarus with polydactyly","bool":false},{"option":"Talipes equinovarus with neural tube defects","bool":true},{"option":"Talipes equinovarus with developmental dysplasia of the hip","bool":false}]},{"id":42,"info":"4th-year/orthopedics/2022","question":"What is the antidote used in the case of acetaminophen poisoning?","answers":[{"option":"N-acetyl cysteine","bool":true},{"option":"Activated charcoal","bool":false},{"option":"Calcium carbonate","bool":false},{"option":"Protamine sulfate","bool":false},{"option":"Sodium bicarbonate","bool":false}]},{"id":43,"info":"4th-year/orthopedics/2022","question":"A patient presents to the outpatient department with complaints of difficulty in swallowing, red eyes, and parotid gland swelling. Anti-ro antibodies and anti-la antibodies are positive. What is the most likely diagnosis?","answers":[{"option":"Undifferentiated autoimmune connective tissue disease","bool":false},{"option":"Systemic sclerosis","bool":false},{"option":"Systemic lupus erythematosus","bool":false},{"option":"Sjogren's syndrome","bool":true},{"option":"Still's disease","bool":false}]},{"id":44,"info":"4th-year/orthopedics/2022","question":"What is the main advantage of the slow sand filter (SSF) over the rapid sand filter (RSF)?","answers":[{"option":"SSF has a greater filtration rate than RSF","bool":false},{"option":"SSF is cheaper to set up than RSF","bool":false},{"option":"SSF requires less area than RSF","bool":false},{"option":"SSF has the same depth as RSF","bool":false},{"option":"SSF provides better purification of water than RSF","bool":true}]},{"id":45,"info":"4th-year/orthopedics/2022","question":"A patient presents with a complaint of knee pain. Investigation results revealed a serum uric acid of 17 mg/dl and urinary uric acid levels of 800 mg/24 hours. After the use of some prescribed first-line medication, the serum uric acid levels were 3.5 mg/dl and urinary uric acid levels were 500 mg/24 hours. Which of the following medications was most likely prescribed to the patient?","answers":[{"option":"Colchicine","bool":false},{"option":"Allopurinol","bool":true},{"option":"Pegloticase","bool":false},{"option":"Naproxen","bool":false},{"option":"Probenecid","bool":false}]},{"id":46,"info":"4th-year/orthopedics/2022","question":"A patient presents with complaints of alopecia, malar rash, and photosensitivity. Her urinalysis shows proteins+ and red blood cells+. What is the most likely diagnosis?","answers":[{"option":"Still's disease","bool":false},{"option":"Rapidly progressive glomerulonephritis","bool":false},{"option":"Systemic sclerosis","bool":false},{"option":"Lupus nephritis","bool":true},{"option":"Sjogren's syndrome","bool":false}]},{"id":47,"info":"4th-year/orthopedics/2022","question":"What is the mechanism of calcium regulation exerted by parathyroid hormone?","answers":[{"option":"Preventing calcium absorption from intestines","bool":false},{"option":"Increasing osteoclast activity and bone resorption","bool":true},{"option":"Decreasing osteoblast activity","bool":false},{"option":"Increasing osteoblast activity","bool":false},{"option":"Inhibiting synthesis of calcitriol by the renal tubules","bool":false}]},{"id":48,"info":"4th-year/orthopedics/2022","question":"What is the purpose of an MRI in a patient with Ewing's sarcoma?","answers":[{"option":"To assess presence of calcification","bool":false},{"option":"To assess the zone of transition","bool":false},{"option":"To guide a biopsy of the lesion","bool":false},{"option":"To assess periosteal reaction","bool":false},{"option":"To assess neurovascular involvement","bool":true}]},{"id":49,"info":"4th-year/orthopedics/2022","question":"A patient presents to the emergency room after a road traffic accident with a fracture in the right forearm. X-ray of the area reveals a distal radius fracture with dislocation of the distal radioulnar joint. What type of fracture is this?","answers":[{"option":"Monteggia fracture","bool":false},{"option":"Colle's fracture","bool":false},{"option":"Galeazzi fracture","bool":true},{"option":"Hutchinson fracture","bool":false},{"option":"Smith fracture","bool":false}]},{"id":50,"info":"4th-year/orthopedics/2022","question":"Which of the following best describes the findings in osteoarthritis?","answers":[{"option":"Swollen Osler's nodes","bool":false},{"option":"Pain in the metacarpophalangeal and proximal interphalangeal joints","bool":false},{"option":"Asymmetric narrowing of joint spaces and osteophyte formation","bool":true},{"option":"Reduced surface area of the affected joints","bool":false},{"option":"Symmetrical narrowing of joint spaces and radiolucent periarticular region.","bool":false}]},{"id":51,"info":"4th-year/orthopedics/2022","question":"What is the normal shape of the cervical spine?","answers":[{"option":"None of these","bool":false},{"option":"Kyphotic","bool":false},{"option":"Lordotic","bool":true},{"option":"Scoliotic","bool":false},{"option":"Oblique","bool":false}]},{"id":52,"info":"4th-year/orthopedics/2022","question":"When is osteoarthritis referred as a primary disorder?","answers":[{"option":"Occurs as a consequence of some other disease","bool":false},{"option":"Occurs after repeated trauma","bool":false},{"option":"Results from low grade trauma","bool":false},{"option":"Results from high grade trauma","bool":false},{"option":"Has no known cause","bool":true}]},{"id":53,"info":"4th-year/orthopedics/2022","question":"A young male patient presents to the clinic with complaints of pain in the knee and ankle joints, redness of the eyes, and pain on micturition. What is the most likely diagnosis?","answers":[{"option":"Rheumatoid arthritis","bool":false},{"option":"Osteoarthritis","bool":false},{"option":"Septic arthritis","bool":false},{"option":"Reiter's syndrome","bool":true},{"option":"Osteomyelitis","bool":false}]},{"id":54,"info":"4th-year/orthopedics/2022","question":"Which of the following processes is catalyzed by hypoxanthine-guanine phosphoribosyltransferase (HGPRT)?","answers":[{"option":"Uric acid synthesis","bool":false},{"option":"Glycolysis","bool":false},{"option":"Purine catabolism","bool":false},{"option":"Kreb's cycle","bool":false},{"option":"Purine salvage","bool":true}]},{"id":55,"info":"4th-year/orthopedics/2022","question":"Endochondral ossification is a process of bone formation that arises in hyaline cartilage. Which of the following bones is formed by endochondral ossification?","answers":[{"option":"Lacrimal bone","bool":false},{"option":"Long bones","bool":true},{"option":"Viscerocranium","bool":false},{"option":"Neurocranium","bool":false},{"option":"Zygomatic bone","bool":false}]},{"id":56,"info":"4th-year/orthopedics/2022","question":"A 40-year-old male presents to the clinic with a complaint of pain in the right metatarsophalangeal joint. He is diagnosed with a case of gout. Deficiency of which of the following enzymes is likely causing hyperuricemia in this patient?","answers":[{"option":"Beta-ureidopropionase","bool":false},{"option":"Uricase","bool":false},{"option":"Dihydropyrimidine dehydrogenase","bool":false},{"option":"Hypoxanthine-guanine phosphoribosyltransferase","bool":true},{"option":"Xanthine oxidase","bool":false}]},{"id":57,"info":"4th-year/orthopedics/2022","question":"A patient was prescribed hydralazine in order to control her hypertension. She later developed a malar rash, photosensitivity, and arthritis. What is the most likely diagnosis in this case?","answers":[{"option":"Sjogren","bool":false},{"option":"Rheumatoid arthritis","bool":false},{"option":"Systemic sclerosis","bool":false},{"option":"Drug-induced lupus","bool":true},{"option":"Systemic lupus erythematosus","bool":false}]},{"id":58,"info":"4th-year/orthopedics/2022","question":"Which of the following teratogens causes phocomelia in the developing fetus?","answers":[{"option":"Thalidomide","bool":true},{"option":"Cocaine","bool":false},{"option":"Diazepam","bool":false},{"option":"Lithium","bool":false},{"option":"Methadone","bool":false}]},{"id":59,"info":"4th-year/orthopedics/2022","question":"Celecoxib is a non-steroidal anti-inflammatory drug (NSAID) having a decreased risk of gastrointestinal bleeding and ulcers as compared to most other NSAIDs. Which of the following is another effect which differentiates celecoxib from most other NSAIDs?","answers":[{"option":"Increased analgesic effect","bool":false},{"option":"No effect on hepatic function","bool":false},{"option":"No effect on platelet aggregation","bool":true},{"option":"Increased anti-pyretic effects","bool":false},{"option":"Reduced anti-inflammatory effects","bool":false}]},{"id":60,"info":"4th-year/orthopedics/2022","question":"An X-ray technician has some concerns regarding X-ray exposure during his job. Which of the following is the most appropriate advice in this case?","answers":[{"option":"Keep the X-ray machine covered at all times","bool":false},{"option":"Transfer to another department","bool":false},{"option":"Leaving the current job","bool":false},{"option":"Wear an aluminum suit while working","bool":false},{"option":"Wear a lead apron while working","bool":true}]},{"id":61,"info":"4th-year/orthopedics/2022","question":"A 33-year-old female, who is a known case of depression and is being treated with sertraline, presents to the clinic with the complaint of generalized body aches. Her laboratory results show serum calcium 2.18 mmol/l, serum phosphate 0.79 mg/dl, alkaline phosphatase 178 IU/l, and parathyroid hormone 15 pg/ml. What is the most likely diagnosis in this case?","answers":[{"option":"Osteopenia","bool":false},{"option":"Osteopetrosis","bool":false},{"option":"Osteomalacia","bool":true},{"option":"Osteoarthritis","bool":false},{"option":"Osteoporosis","bool":false}]},{"id":62,"info":"4th-year/orthopedics/2022","question":"A farmer presented to the emergency room with a complaint of a snake bite on his foot. On examination, a superficial bite mark was seen by a non-venomous snake. After disinfecting the wound, what would be the most appropriate next step in the management of this patient?","answers":[{"option":"Find the snake which caused the bite","bool":false},{"option":"Administer a high dose of heparin and steroids","bool":false},{"option":"Administer tetanus and rabies vaccine","bool":false},{"option":"Administer anti-venom","bool":false},{"option":"Start prophylaxis for gas gangrene","bool":true}]},{"id":63,"info":"4th-year/orthopedics/2022","question":"What is the most common management for fractures of diaphysis of long bones?","answers":[{"option":"Wires","bool":false},{"option":"Plating","bool":false},{"option":"Conservative","bool":false},{"option":"Screwing","bool":false},{"option":"Nailing","bool":true}]},{"id":64,"info":"4th-year/orthopedics/2022","question":"Which of the following gases may be fatal if it is high in concentration in closed places like homes?","answers":[{"option":"Respiratory particles","bool":false},{"option":"Radon","bool":false},{"option":"Carbon dioxide","bool":false},{"option":"Carbon monoxide","bool":true},{"option":"Nitrous oxide","bool":false}]},{"id":65,"info":"4th-year/orthopedics/2022","question":"Which of the following is the most consistent feature of hip osteoarthritis?","answers":[{"option":"Difficulty in walking","bool":false},{"option":"Difficulty in running","bool":false},{"option":"Pain on jumping","bool":false},{"option":"Difficulty in squatting","bool":false},{"option":"Groin pain","bool":true}]},{"id":66,"info":"4th-year/orthopedics/2022","question":"A child presents to the clinic with the complaint of pain and swelling in the right knee, left ankle, and small joints of hands and feet. He had a history of fever one month back. He has increased platelets but a normal total leucocyte count. What is the most likely diagnosis?","answers":[{"option":"Reactive arthritis","bool":false},{"option":"Septic arthritis","bool":false},{"option":"Hemophilia","bool":false},{"option":"Osteoarthritis","bool":false},{"option":"Juvenile rheumatoid arthritis","bool":true}]},{"id":67,"info":"4th-year/orthopedics/2022","question":"A 25-year-old female presents to an orthopedic clinic with a history of a fall on an outstretched hand 2 days ago. She sustained a fracture in her right radius at its distal end. Which of the following is the appropriate stage of healing fracture in this case?","answers":[{"option":"Reparative phase","bool":false},{"option":"Remodeling phase","bool":false},{"option":"Resorption phase","bool":false},{"option":"Consolidation phase","bool":false},{"option":"Inflammatory phase","bool":true}]},{"id":68,"info":"4th-year/orthopedics/2022","question":"A 3-year-old girl is brought to the clinic by her mother with persistent diarrhea. The mother reports that the local water supply is salty. What practical advice can be given to treat the temporary hardness in this water, and consequently improve the child's condition?","answers":[{"option":"Base exchange","bool":false},{"option":"Boiling","bool":true},{"option":"Permutit process","bool":false},{"option":"Addition of lime","bool":false},{"option":"Addition of caustic soda","bool":false}]},{"id":69,"info":"4th-year/orthopedics/2022","question":"Why are NSAIDs preferred over colchicine for acute gout flares?","answers":[{"option":"They have a more rapid action","bool":false},{"option":"They have a longer duration of action","bool":false},{"option":"They are more effective","bool":false},{"option":"They are better tolerated","bool":true},{"option":"They have uricosuric and analgesic effect","bool":false}]},{"id":70,"info":"4th-year/orthopedics/2022","question":"A 6-year-old came with short stature below the 3rd percentile. His family has short stature from his father's side. He has frontal bossing, depressed nasal bridge, rhizomelia of lower limbs, and has frequent ear infections. He is also found to have kyphosis. What is the most likely diagnosis?","answers":[{"option":"Achondroplasia","bool":true},{"option":"Hurler syndrome","bool":false},{"option":"Spondyloepiphyseal dysgenesis","bool":false},{"option":"Metaphyseal dysgenesis","bool":false},{"option":"Constitutional growth delay","bool":false}]},{"id":71,"info":"4th-year/orthopedics/2022","question":"Which of the following gases is known to seep out from under houses and leak during construction/digging of earth, and potentially cause lung cancer?","answers":[{"option":"Radon","bool":true},{"option":"Carbon monoxide","bool":false},{"option":"Nitrous oxide","bool":false},{"option":"Hydrogen sulfide","bool":false},{"option":"Chloroform","bool":false}]},{"id":72,"info":"4th-year/orthopedics/2022","question":"Which of the following drugs selectively inhibits the cyclooxygenase-2 enzyme?","answers":[{"option":"Ibuprofen","bool":false},{"option":"Diclofenac","bool":false},{"option":"Phenylbutazone","bool":false},{"option":"Rofecoxib","bool":true},{"option":"Ketorolac","bool":false}]},{"id":73,"info":"4th-year/orthopedics/2022","question":"Which of the following terms best defines a sequestrum?","answers":[{"option":"Brodie abscess","bool":false},{"option":"Dead bone","bool":true},{"option":"New bone","bool":false},{"option":"Sclerotic bone","bool":false},{"option":"Reactive bone","bool":false}]},{"id":74,"info":"4th-year/orthopedics/2022","question":"Which of the following inhibits bone resorption?","answers":[{"option":"Estrogen/testosterone","bool":true},{"option":"Parathyroid hormone","bool":false},{"option":"Corticosteroids","bool":false},{"option":"Tumor necrosis factor","bool":false},{"option":"Interleukin-1","bool":false}]},{"id":75,"info":"4th-year/orthopedics/2022","question":"A 35-year-old male presents to the clinic with bone pain and fever. A presumptive diagnosis of osteomyelitis is made. Culture reveals the presence of gram-negative diplococci. What is the most likely causative organism?","answers":[{"option":"Klebsiella","bool":false},{"option":"Escherichia coli","bool":false},{"option":"Neisseria gonorrhoeae","bool":true},{"option":"Staphylococcus aureus","bool":false},{"option":"Pseudomonas aeruginosa","bool":false}]},{"id":76,"info":"4th-year/orthopedics/2022","question":"A 9-year-old child is brought to the clinic with pain in the right leg associated with swelling. X-ray reveals evidence of Brodie's abscess. What is the most likely diagnosis?","answers":[{"option":"Osteosarcoma","bool":false},{"option":"Arthritis","bool":false},{"option":"Rickets","bool":false},{"option":"Osteomyelitis","bool":true},{"option":"Osteopenia","bool":false}]},{"id":77,"info":"4th-year/orthopedics/2022","question":"A newborn is noticed to have the right upper limb missing from the forearm onward. Which term best describes this condition?","answers":[{"option":"Phocomelia","bool":false},{"option":"Amelia","bool":false},{"option":"Meromelia","bool":true},{"option":"Micromelia","bool":false},{"option":"Rhizomelia","bool":false}]},{"id":78,"info":"4th-year/orthopedics/2022","question":"Impairment in the function of which of the following cell types results in osteopetrosis?","answers":[{"option":"Chondrocyte","bool":false},{"option":"Chondroblast","bool":false},{"option":"Osteoclast","bool":true},{"option":"Osteoblast","bool":false},{"option":"Osteocyte","bool":false}]},{"id":79,"info":"4th-year/orthopedics/2022","question":"An intravenous drug user presents with the complaint of burning micturition and fever for 3 days. He also has gritty eyes and lower back pain for the past 3 months. He also has an ulcer on the glans of the penis. What is the most likely cause of these symptoms?","answers":[{"option":"N. Gonorrhea infection","bool":false},{"option":"Tertiary syphilis","bool":false},{"option":"HIV infection","bool":false},{"option":"Reiter's syndrome","bool":true},{"option":"Behcet's syndrome","bool":false}]},{"id":80,"info":"4th-year/orthopedics/2022","question":"A child presents to the emergency department with a radius fracture. The surgeon wants to preserve the periosteum. What is the most likely reason for preserving the periosteum?","answers":[{"option":"It is osteogenic","bool":true},{"option":"It produces new cells","bool":false},{"option":"It is protective","bool":false},{"option":"It provides attachment to tendons","bool":false},{"option":"It provides muscle attachment","bool":false}]},{"id":81,"info":"4th-year/orthopedics/2022","question":"A 45-year-old male patient presents to the clinic with a complaint of dull hip pain for 3 years. On investigation, there is a mass of 10 cm × 13 cm attached to the hips which has irregular borders. Removal of the mass from ischium for biopsy reveals spotty calcifications. The transverse section of the mass reveals a blue-gray color. What is the most likely diagnosis?","answers":[{"option":"Chondrosarcoma","bool":true},{"option":"Ewing sarcoma","bool":false},{"option":"Enchondroma","bool":false},{"option":"Osteosarcoma","bool":false},{"option":"Giant cell tumor","bool":false}]},{"id":82,"info":"4th-year/orthopedics/2022","question":"A female G2 P1 presents to the clinic in the 21st week of gestation as she is not feeling fetal movements. On investigation, the fetus seems short-statured. The fetus is delivered at the 28th week of gestation as a stillborn baby and is noticed to have blue sclerae. What is the most likely diagnosis?","answers":[{"option":"Mucopolysaccharidoses","bool":false},{"option":"Rickets","bool":false},{"option":"Osteopetrosis","bool":false},{"option":"Osteogenesis imperfecta","bool":true},{"option":"Achondroplasia","bool":false}]},{"id":83,"info":"4th-year/orthopedics/2022","question":"An athlete wishes to improve his physical performance. His sports physician recommends gradually increasing his exertion during his workout routine. What is this technique called?","answers":[{"option":"Increased repititions","bool":false},{"option":"Progressive overload","bool":true},{"option":"Planned variation","bool":false},{"option":"Power-lifting","bool":false},{"option":"Prioritization","bool":false}]},{"id":84,"info":"4th-year/orthopedics/2022","question":"Which section of the manuscript does not have references?","answers":[{"option":"Result and discussion","bool":false},{"option":"Methodology and abstract","bool":false},{"option":"Result and abstract","bool":true},{"option":"Introduction and methodology","bool":false},{"option":"Abstract and discussion","bool":false}]},{"id":85,"info":"4th-year/orthopedics/2022","question":"Which of the following sections contains the research objectives in a manuscript?","answers":[{"option":"Abstract","bool":false},{"option":"Result","bool":false},{"option":"Methodology","bool":false},{"option":"Introduction","bool":true},{"option":"Discussion","bool":false}]},{"id":86,"info":"4th-year/orthopedics/2022","question":"A researcher wants to add weightage to their own arguments in a research paper. Which of the following sections needs strong references to fulfill this purpose?","answers":[{"option":"Result","bool":false},{"option":"Methodology","bool":false},{"option":"Abstract","bool":false},{"option":"Introduction","bool":false},{"option":"Discussion","bool":true}]},{"id":87,"info":"4th-year/orthopedics/2022","question":"What is the most appropriate treatment for a fracture of the shaft of the femur?","answers":[{"option":"Dynamic hip screw","bool":false},{"option":"Splintage","bool":false},{"option":"K-wires","bool":false},{"option":"Plates and screws","bool":false},{"option":"Nailing","bool":true}]},{"id":88,"info":"4th-year/orthopedics/2022","question":"How long after radiation exposure does leukemia develop?","answers":[{"option":"10 weeks","bool":false},{"option":"10 years","bool":false},{"option":"A few days","bool":false},{"option":"2 to 5 years","bool":false},{"option":"5 or more years","bool":true}]},{"id":89,"info":"4th-year/orthopedics/2022","question":"An industrial worker operates machinery remotely to avoid being exposed to hazardous substances. What is the technical term used for this safety method?","answers":[{"option":"Total enclosure","bool":true},{"option":"Ventilation","bool":false},{"option":"Dust suppression","bool":false},{"option":"Procedure segregation","bool":false},{"option":"Housekeeping","bool":false}]},{"id":90,"info":"4th-year/orthopedics/2022","question":"What is the term used to describe the use of less toxic substances in place of more toxic substances?","answers":[{"option":"Segregation of process","bool":false},{"option":"Total enclosure","bool":false},{"option":"Elimination","bool":false},{"option":"Substitution","bool":true},{"option":"Engineering control","bool":false}]},{"id":91,"info":"4th-year/orthopedics/2022","question":"Which of the following statements is true for the normal effects of aging on cognition?","answers":[{"option":"Short term memory declines","bool":false},{"option":"Working memory is maintained","bool":false},{"option":"There is agitation and reduced alertness","bool":false},{"option":"Long term memory declines overall","bool":false},{"option":"Long term memory declines except for remote memories of emotional significance","bool":true}]},{"id":92,"info":"4th-year/orthopedics/2022","question":"A baby dies in utero due to multiple fractures. What is the most likely mutation causing this condition?","answers":[{"option":"Type 1 collagen gene mutation","bool":true},{"option":"RB","bool":false},{"option":"TCIRG1","bool":false},{"option":"CLCN7","bool":false},{"option":"FGFR3","bool":false}]},{"id":93,"info":"4th-year/orthopedics/2022","question":"Which of the following conditions is the most appropriate consequence of hypoxanthine-guanine phosphoribosyltransferase (HGPRT) deficiency?","answers":[{"option":"Von-Gierke disease","bool":false},{"option":"Lesch-Nyhan syndrome","bool":true},{"option":"Pseudogout","bool":false},{"option":"Tay-sachs disease","bool":false},{"option":"Gout","bool":false}]},{"id":94,"info":"4th-year/orthopedics/2022","question":"What is the term used to describe the medical care of the elderly population?","answers":[{"option":"Physiatrist","bool":false},{"option":"Geriatrics","bool":true},{"option":"Gerontology","bool":false},{"option":"Podiatry","bool":false},{"option":"Pediatrics","bool":false}]},{"id":95,"info":"4th-year/orthopedics/2022","question":"Which of the following tissues gives rise to intramembranous bones?","answers":[{"option":"Sclerotome","bool":false},{"option":"Fibrocartilage","bool":false},{"option":"Cartilage","bool":false},{"option":"Mesenchyme","bool":true},{"option":"Osteoid","bool":false}]},{"id":96,"info":"4th-year/orthopedics/2022","question":"Which compound is responsible for the viscosity of synovial fluid?","answers":[{"option":"Lubricin","bool":false},{"option":"Collagenases","bool":false},{"option":"Hyaluronic acid","bool":true},{"option":"Heparan sulfate","bool":false},{"option":"Prostaglandins","bool":false}]}]
export default arr